<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root><Source> Independent.co.uk</Source><Date> Fr 2019-05-10</Date><Place> Berlin</Place><Title> Berlin park creates 'pink zone' spaces for drug dealers to carry out transactions</Title><Subtitle> </Subtitle><Author> Adam Forrest</Author><Article> Drug dealers in Berlin have been given designated sections of a city centre park to conduct business in a bid to keep them away from families and joggers. Cengiz Demirci  manager of the popular Goerlitzer Park in the fashionable Kreuzberg area  said the pink lines had been spray-painted around sanctioned drug zones to let everyone know where purchases could take place. Mr Demirci claimed it would encourage people who had become intimidated by gangs of dealers back into the park. This method has purely practical reasoning behind it. Its not that were legalising the selling of drugs, he told radio station RBB. Both city and federal authorities strongly condemned the move. Germanys drug czar Marlene Mortler lambasted the creation of special zones, saying it appeared to give people license to trade. Berlins top security official, interior minister Andreas Geisel, said the park managers idea would not be adopted across the rest city. He said: Police are fighting drug trafficking, including in Goerlitzer Park.  According to The Local websites German edition, drug dealers have not been paying any attention to the spray-painted lines in the park  known locally as the Gorli. Yet Mr Demirci pledged to continue his experimental policy to try to tackle anti-social behaviour problems in his park, where clashes between competing dealers have been known.  Explaining many dealers were from west Africa  including some not allowed to work while waiting on asylum claims to be processed  the park manager said letting them to earn money legally would help address the issue. Then 90 percent of the activity would stop here immediately. A spokesperson for the district of Friedrichshain-Kreuzberg, which employs Mr Demirci as the park manager, said: It is the task of the park manager to find solutions to the conflicts in Goerlitzer Park within the scope of his possibilities.  The approach with the coloured markings on the sidewalks, however, is not coordinated with the district office and [the markings] will be well considered and discussed by the relevant committees. Only the best news in your inbox  Kurt Wansner, a CDU politician representing Friedrichshain-Kreuzberg at the House of Representatives of Berlin, called the experiment absurd. He said: It is completely absurd and unacceptable for the district to promote drug sales and consumption in Goerlitzer Park with its park managers. [The demarcations] torpedo all efforts to get the drug problem under control there.</Article><Additional> </Additional><Link> https://www.independent.co.uk/news/world/europe/berlin-drug-dealers-park-legal-pink-zone-goerlitzer-cengiz-demirci-a8907311.html</Link></root>