<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root><Source> BZ</Source><Date> So 2019-09-08</Date><Place> </Place><Title> The drug dealers at RAW in Friedrichshain are only 14 years old!</Title><Subtitle> </Subtitle><Author> Hildburg Bruns</Author><Article> An ultra cool party weekend? Yes, thats Berlin, too. Three days of nonstop celebrating, or more. Especially tourists see this as an ideal vacation, and they have one magical address in mind: the RAW compound in Friedrichshain, a former train repair area. It's not only a mystical partly zone, but also a dangerous one.  Dr. Franziska Becker, an expert for conflict solving, has examined the area for Berlins city authorities. Her aim: finding ways to minimize violence. Miss Becker interviewed 72 people, from residents to police officers to circus artists. She accompanied police squads, roamed the party zone until 7 am, she even talked with frustrated city clerks. Der Eingang zum RAW-Gelaende in der Revaler Strasse. A magnet for party tourists: the RAW compound in Friedrichshain. The truly shocking results of Miss Beckers inquiries: the dealers and consumers of drugs are increasingly younger. 11 year old students are chatted up; 14 year old Arab boys sell their toxic wares. The problems start at Warschauer Bridge where 85,000 people change trains daily. It is a pickpocket paradise; they throw their loot over the bridge and pick it up later. It is a drug dealers Eldorado, too. We will soon have a situation comparable to Goerli  Friedrichshains local politician Sven Heinemann (40, SPD) counted two dozen dealers on a regular Thursday evening while he was walking from the train station to Simon Dach Street. Along the way, three people openly offered him drugs. If this continues, we will soon have a situation like there is near the subway station Goerlitzer Bahnhof. The German transport system needs to reconsider the cancellation of its permanent night security personnel. Additionally, the police needs to go after dealers and their clients in a more radical way. The turning point  In the early hours of the day, in August 2015, singer Jennifer Rostock was robed, her companion attacked with a knife. Her Facebook post, describing what happened, was shared 43,000 times. These people are really dangerous and wont shy away from anything  they would even kill for a fucking necklace. The number of visitors to the area went down, more money was invested into security. In July, a portable police station was installed; since September 2017 police officers have used video surveillance cameras on Warschauer Bridge. The officers even put stickers with warnings onto the pack packs of tourists, alerting them about thieves.  On the RAW compound brighter lamps have been put in, they were smashed soon after. A portable public toilet had to be closed after drug use was registered and the cleaning personnel assaulted. The owner of the RAW hired special security personnel, up to eight people, to patrol the area around the clock. But once the crime figures went down again, these security guards were let go  they were too expensive. The consequences are fatal: There is a vacuum now, a police officer told Dr. Franziska Becker.  A police boss  We have noticed that the clients are getting younger and younger, as are the dealers. Its not unusual to see 14 year olds selling drugs. His colleagues say, most of the young men are underage refugees; they have no permanent address, they sleep on graveyards, playgrounds, in parks, with buddies. In their refugee accommodations (e.g. in Bernau and Ahrensfelde) they are banned; or they ran away, fearing being deported. They meet in groups of 25, also on Alexanderplatz. The Arabs arrive at RAW at night, chasing off the African dealers. Theft prevention: in 2016 the police explained to RAW visitors the tricks of pick pockets A caretaker  From 2015 onwards there have been the so called dance routines on the compound. Were talking of groups of four to five people. One robs you, the other calls for help, to draw away your attention. Meanwhile, a person who has danced up to you runs away with your wallet. Its a completely choreographed affair.  A security staff member  Ive walked every corner of this compound. Ive seen women in dark corners, girls who have travelled to Berlin. While they are high on drugs they lose their friends and are easy prey for the night. In 2015/16 this area has become a nightmare zone. Women who went to the Haubentaucher swimming pool in the afternoon, for sunbathing, are afraid of returning to their cars after sunset.  On weekends there is a lot of action on the RAW compound.  A young woman from Friedrichshain  Among my girl friends there is no one who doesnt have pepper spray on her. And none of us would go out alone after sunset. The sexual assaults (e.g. grabbing women in the genital area) are mostly done by Arab speaking men.  A shop owner  From 2005 till 2012 things were okay here. But since the drug dealers have arrived there is turmoil. You need to be scared to simply walk down Revaler Street at night. Every two meters theres another dealer. Mostly they are there for the tourists, but as shop owners we have to live with the consequences.  A hostel owner  What I am really worried about is that something happens at night. Since the end of last year Arab speaking groups have started meeting here to beat each other up. They attack one another with broken bottles; they seem to be under the obvious influence of drugs. The hostel owner has now hired two Arabs as night porters; he has also installed surveillance cameras. Nonetheless, there are regular burglaries and broken windows. A neighbor  This is purely a nightlife situation. You get loud noise, garbage everywhere, drug dealers, there are too many people using limited public space. Traffic here is chaotic on weekends. This is a residential area, is was not designed to accommodate such multitudes of people. Things become unbearable from the end of May onwards. Theres a party on every little spot of grass. The social worker has been living in this neighborhood for 20 years. The shop owners complain about the rise in drug dealing. A politician  My daughter is 11 years old. She was chatted up the other day on Warschauer Bridge, someone asked her if she wanted cocaine. Shes in fifth grade! Its completely normal here that kids are being offered drugs. Party tourists are responsible for themselves, you might say, but that 11 year old girls are dragged into this makes me really angry!  A restaurant owner  The ever increasing noise level here has to do with the never-ending new late night shops, so called Spaetis. On top of that, there are petrol stations selling alcohol. No one goes into a restaurant or bar anymore, they all buy their beer at the Spaeti, then they sit outside on a bench and drink. These shops sell alcohol to anyone, they never ask if the customer should still be drinking if hes already pissed. Afterward the young men move onto the RAW compound with whiskey bottles in their hands and roam around. Berlins police tries to demonstrate more presence in the area surrounding the RAW compound (photo: spreepicture) This is how the crime scene has developed   Drug offences near Warschauer Bridge:  There were 80 cases of illegal possession and 80 cases of illegal dealings with drugs in 2011. In the first half of 2018 there were 148 arrested dealers and 344 cases of illegal drug possession.    Assaults near Warschauer Bridge: 640 in 2016, 654 in 2017, 306 until June 2018.   Number of registered thefts near Warschauer Bride: 709 (2016), 427 (2017), 203 (2018 until June).   Registered crimes by day (in one year): 122 on Mondays, 117 on Tuesdays, 133 on Wednesdays, 166 on Thursdays, 236 on Fridays, 435 on Saturdays, 402 on Sundays. Obviously, theres a clear increase towards the weekend.   Times of assaults on Sundays (between 2013 and 2015): 514 cases from midnight to 6 am; 84 cases between 6 am and noon; 20 cases between noon and 6 pm; 27 cases between 6 pm and midnight. In other words, you need to be especially careful when a new day dawns.</Article><Additional> </Additional><Link> https://www.bz-berlin.de/berlin/friedrichshain-kreuzberg/the-drug-dealers-at-raw-in-friedrichshain-are-only-14-years-old</Link></root>